# María Cecilia Urrutia Lois Backend Developer Jr. | QA Tester | UX Analyst

urrutia.cici@gmail.com | Phone: +54 911 67280356 | LinkedIn | Github | Website

#### Professional Profile

Professional with 13 years of experience in digital development, bringing expertise in various roles across multidisciplinary teams, including content manager, frontend developer, UX analyst. I like backend development. Technologies: Python | Java | Spring | UML | SQL | MongoDB | NodeJS | JMeter | Selenium | Postman.

## Professional Experience

Web Developer | QA Tester | Buenos Aires City Government | Buenos Aires, Argentina | Oct 2013 – Now (HYBRID)

Digital content management in Drupal and WordPress.

MySQL databases, collaborating with the Open Data department at GCBA.

Manual QA tester, performing functional and regression testing.

Wordpress Developer | QA Tester | Vacunar S.A. | Buenos Aires, Argentina | July 2018 – Feb 2024 (REMOTE)

WordPress development, maintenance, and QA Tester. APIs Tester.

## Education | Licence | Certifications

Backend Programmer | Centro de Formación Profesional 17 | Buenos Aires, Argentina | 2023-2024 Cinematography Photography | SICA (Sindicato de la Industria Cinematográfica Argentina) | 2002 Commercial High School Graduate | Instituto Casa de Jesús | Buenos Aires, Argentina | 1989

Introduction to Data Science with Python | Desafío Latam | Expedition: ago. 2024 | Credential ID

**Django Framework** | Agencia de Habilidades para el Futuro, Buenos Aires City Government Program | Expedition: may 2024 | <u>Credential ID</u>

MongoDB | EducacionIT | Expedición: mar. 2024 | Credential ID

Introducción a Java | EducacionIT | Expedition: dic. 2023 | Credential ID

Technical English for IT | PEI 4 B2 | Pearson | Expedition: nov. 2023 | Diploma

**Full Stack Python** | Agencia de Habilidades para el Futuro, Buenos Aires City Government Program | Expedition 2023 | <u>Diploma</u>

**Testing QA** | Agencia de Habilidades para el Futuro | Buenos Aires City Government Program | Expedition: sept. 2023 | <u>Diploma</u>

Backend Programmer | IFS 17 | Buenos Aires, Argentina | 2023-2024

**Bookstore Legacy Shop.**Technologies: NodeJs, Express, MongoDB Atlas. Library management system, backend and frontend using Bootstrap. <a href="https://bookstorefrontend-henna.vercel.app/">https://bookstorefrontend-henna.vercel.app/</a>

**DJFlix:** Technologies: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Api Restful. Crunchyroll clone for fun. <a href="https://urrutiace.pythonanywhere.com/">https://urrutiace.pythonanywhere.com/</a>

**Login Register Auth.** Technologies: NodeJs, Express, Bcrypt, JWT. Login Register Auth, Profile, Admin site authentication app. https://github.com/ceurrutia/login-register-auth

### Skills

**Technical:** Product Management, Agile Methodologies (Scrum, Kanban), UX/UI Design, NodeJs, Python, Django, Java, UML,MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Rapize, JMeter, Postman.

**Soft Skills:** Leadership, Communication, Problem-solving, Adaptability, Teamwork, Organization, Attention to detail.

Languages: English (B2), Spanish (Native), Japanese (Basic).